Rudolph Troike Bilingual Education Collection 1953-1988 (bulk 1974-1988)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series II: Publications, 1957-1988; undated
  - Subseries 4: Reports and Evaluations
    - U.S Department of Health, Education, and Welfare-The Status of Bilingual Vocational Training Report of the Commissioner of Education and the Secretary of Labor to the President and to the Congress, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - U.S Office of Education-National Conference on Bilingual Education: Language Skills Final Report, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - U.S Office of Education-Report to the Congress on Bilingual Education an Unmet Need, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - U.S Office of Education Division of Bilingual Education-Individualized Bilingual Instruction Final Evaluation, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - U.S Office of Education Division of Bilingual Education-The Title VII (Bilingual Education) Fellowship Program a Report on the Graduates of the Program During Academic Year 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Series III: Research Files, 1953-1988; undated
  This series is arranged topically and alphabetically. This series contains research materials collected, used, and overseen by Troike. These research files address a range of topics within the subject of bilingual education and bilingualism, such as legislation and policy making, and geographic and ethnic diversities. Case studies, reports, newspaper clippings, conference materials, and other items are part of this series. Some of the materials are in other languages such as Spanish, French, and various indigenous languages. These materials are scattered throughout the collection, but are mostly concentrated in subseries two and five.
  - Subseries 1: Conference Materials
    - Academic Excellence and Equity through Bilingual Education the Fifteenth Annual International Bilingual Bicultural Education Conference of the National Association for Bilingual Education, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Assorted Statements and Paper Presentations, 1966; 1976-1978 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Assorted Statements and Paper Presentations, 1979-1984; undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Conference on Development of Bilingualism in Children of Varying Linguistic and Cultural Heritages, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare Conference on Language Research and Model Bilingual Schools Itinerary, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Desegregation and Education Concerns of the Hispanic Community Conference, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - The Education of Hispanics: Midwest Conference Proceedings, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Eighth Annual International Bilingual Bicultural Education Conference of the National Association for Bilingual Education, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Eleventh Annual International Bilingual Bicultural Education Conference of the National Association for Bilingual Education, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - First Annual International Multilingual Multicultural Conference Proceedings, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - National Association for Bilingual Education Conference Directory of Presenters, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - National Conference of Early Childhood Education and the Chicanito, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Proceedings of the National Planned Variation Bilingual Models Conference, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Program for Educational Opportunity Bilingual Bicultural Education Conference, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Roundtable on Bilingual Education in Washington, D.C, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Sixth Annual International Bilingual Bicultural Education Conference, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - White House Conference on Aging: The Spanish Speaking Elderly, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - White House Mini-Conference on Hispanic Aging, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Synthesis of Bilingual Clearinghouse Conferences, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Thirteenth Annual International Bilingual Bicultural Education Conference of the National Association for Bilingual Education, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Subseries 2: Ethnic Groups
    - Asians-Directories of Programs, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Asians-Japanese, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Asians-Manual for Indochinese Refugee Education, 1967-1977 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Asians-Professional Papers, 1981; undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Asians-Reports, Summaries, and Surveys, 1974; 1978-1980,; 1983 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Latinos-Case Studies, 1973-1979; 1981-1983 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Latinos-Early Childhood Education, 1968; 1972-1982 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Latinos-General Reports, 1973-1974; 1981-1984 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Latinos-Journal and Newspaper Articles, 1969; 1973-1983 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Latinos-Mexican Americans-Advisory Committee for the Education of the Spanish Speaking and Mexican Americans Annual Report: A Challenge to Reality, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Latinos-Mexican Americans-U.S Commission on Civil Rights’ Report on the Mexican American Education Study, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Latinos-Professional Papers, 1975-1979; 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Latinos-Population Reports and Statistics, 1976; 1979-1985 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Latinos-Puerto Ricans, 1978; 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Latinos-Puerto Ricans-Final Report from the National Institute of Education on Local Reasoning Skills of Puerto Rican Bilinguals, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Mental Ability Score Sheet by Various Ethnic Groups, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Native Americans–Alaska-Bilingual Education Materials, 1973-1974; 1979 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Native Americans–Alaska-Bilingual Education Materials, 1985; undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Native Americans–Alaska-Bilingual Education Materials, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Native Americans-Assorted Bilingual Education Materials, 1969; 1972-1986 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Native Americans-Bibliographies, 1975; 1982 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Native Americans-Case Studies, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Native Americans-Cherokee, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Native Americans-Choctaw, 1984; 1986 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Native Americans-Early Childhood Education, 1973-1975; undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Native Americans-Hopi, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Native Americans-Journal Articles, 1978-1984; undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Native Americans-Navajo, 1974-1978; 1985 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Native Americans-Navajo-First, Third, and Fourth Quarterly Progress Reports of a Ethnographic and Sociolinguistic Study of an Exemplary Bilingual Education Program, 1981; undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Native Americans-Navajo-Fifth Quarterly Progress Reports of a Ethnographic and Sociolinguistic Study of an Exemplary Bilingual Education Program, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Native Americans-Report-American Indian Language Education by William Leap, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Native Americans-Report-Indian Languages and Indian Education: Concerns in Indian Education in the American Midwest, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Native Americans-Report-Center for Applied Linguistics on Language Policy in the Bureau of Indian Affairs, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Native Americans-Report-The Eleventh National Advisory Council on Indian Education about Meeting the Challenges of Educational Change for Indian People, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Native Americans-Report-The Tenth Annual National Advisory Council on Indian Education about the Indian Education Act: Indian Students Have the Right to Excellence in Education, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Native Americans-Report-The Thirteenth Annual National Advisory Council on Indian Education about Indian Education: Focus on Past, Present, and Future, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Native Americans-Reports-Bilingual Education and Teacher Training, 1968-1973 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Native Americans-Sahaptin River Tribes, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Sixty-first American Assembly of Ethnic Groups in the United States, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 3: Federal and State Legislations and Regulations
    - Academic Equity and Excellence through the Bilingual Education Act of 1984, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Adult Education Act and Bilingualism, 1975-1979; undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Ashbrook Amendment, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Assorted Court Cases, 1974-1978 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Assorted Press Statements from the Government, 1971; 1978-1981 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Bilingual Education Act/Title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act Migrant Education Program-Assorted Materials, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Bilingual Education Act/Title VII of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act-Dissemination and Assessment Center for Bilingual Education Bilingual Bicultural Program Guides, 1977-1979 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Bilingual Education Act/Title VII of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act-National Clearinghouse for Bilingual Education Bilingual Education Program Guide, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Bilingual Education Act/Title VII of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act-National Clearinghouse for Bilingual Education Bilingual Education Program Guide, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Bilingual Education Act/Title VII of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1968-1974 Amendments, 1973-1975 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Bilingual Education Act/Title VII of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1968-1978 Amendments, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Bilingual Education Act/Title VII of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1968-1984 Amendments, 1982-1984; undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Bilingual Education Act/Title VII of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1968-Assorted Materials, 1977-1988; undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Bilingual Education Act/Title VII of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1968-Policy Recommendations by the Center of Applied Linguistics, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Bilingual Education Act/Title VII of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1968-Proposed Amendments and Regulations, 1980-1982; undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Bilingual Education Act/Title VII of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1968-Studies and Program Evaluation Materials, 1976-1984; undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Bilingual Education Act/Title VII of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act Spanish English Bilingual Education Program-System Documentation for Impact Study, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Bilingual Education Act/Title VII of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act Spanish English Bilingual Education Program-AIR Impact Studies and Evaluations of Program, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Bilingual Education and Desegregation Materials, 1977; undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Education Amendments of 1978, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - General Materials, 1974-1982 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Lau V. Nichols-Assorted Materials, 1974-1981 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Lau V. Nichols-Court Materials, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Lau V. Nichols-Lau Compliance Models, 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Lau V. Nichols-Lau Task Force National Conference on Research and Policy Implications Report, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Lau V. Nichols-Regulations, 1975-1980 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Lau V. Nichols-Remedies, 1970; 1974-1982 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Labor/HEW Appropriations Bill, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Model Bilingual Education Law, 1973-1975 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Proposed Bilingual Regulations, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Public Law: Joint Resolution, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Refugee Act of 1980 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, 1980-1981; 1984 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Subseries 4: General Bilingual Education Materials
    - Assorted Printed Journal Articles, 1962; 1966,; 1974-1976 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Assorted Printed Journal Articles, 1977-1979 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Assorted Printed Journal Articles, 1980-1982 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Assorted Printed Journal Articles, 1983-1987 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Assorted Printed Journal Articles, undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Assorted Professional Papers, 1970-1977 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Assorted Professional Papers, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Assorted Professional Papers, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Assorted Professional Papers, 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Assorted Professional Papers, 1984-1986 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Assorted Professional Papers, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Bibliographies, 1977; 1980,; undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Bilingual Vocational Training-Abstracts, 1976-1978 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Bilingual Vocational Training-Strategies for Outreach Services Proposal, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Bilingual Vocational Training-Assorted Materials, 1977-1982; 1988 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Bilingual Vocational Programs Information Packet, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Bilingual Special Education, 1986-1987; undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Case Studies and Research-Significant Bilingual Instructional Features Study-Assorted Materials, 1981-1983 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Case Studies and Research-Significant Bilingual Instructional Features Study-Report, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Case Studies and Research-Children’s English and Services Study, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Case Studies and Research-Lists of Various Bilingual Education Projects, 1975; 1980-1983 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Case Studies and Research-Program for Persons of Limited English Speaking Ability U.S Case Studies, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Case Studies and Research-Special Studies of Language Usage in the U.S, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Case Studies and Research-U.S Bilingual Education Programs, 1975-1984; 1986 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Case Studies and Research- United States Census Materials, 1975; 1979-1983 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Degree Programs in Bilingual Education, 1974-1979; undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Measure of English Language Proficiency (MELP) Study Materials, 1976-1980 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - National Association for Bilingual Education-Secretary H. Terrell Bell Interview at the NABE Convention, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - National Center for Education Statistics-Assorted Materials, 1975; undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - National Center for Education Statistics-Memorandums, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - National Clearinghouse for Bilingual Education-Calendars and Product Lists, 1979; 1983-1985,; undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - National Institute of Education-Fiscal Year Program Plans, 1974-1979 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - National Institute of Education-Research Grants Program Materials, 1977-1979; 1983 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Newspaper Clippings-Bilingual Education and Bilingualism, 1974-1979 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper Clippings-Bilingual Education and Bilingualism, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper Clippings-Bilingual Education and Bilingualism, 1982-1984 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Newspaper Clippings-Bilingual Education and Bilingualism, 1985-1986 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Newspaper Clippings-Bilingual Education and Bilingualism, 1987-1988; undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Phone Directories, 1981; undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Research Funding Materials, 1979-1980; 1984,; undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Southwest Educational Development Laboratory (SEDL)-Assorted Materials, 1976-1977 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Surveys, 1975; 1981-1982,; undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Surveys-National Center for Educational Statistics, 1976-1978 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - United States Xenophobia Fact Sheet, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Subseries 5: International
    - Australia, 1973-1987 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Bolivia, 1974-1983 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Bolivia-Bilingual Education Grant Project Reports, 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Canada, 1973-1981; undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Canada-French Immersion Programs, 1975-1976; 1987 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Colombia, 1972; 1978,; undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Ecuador-Assorted Materials, 1973-1979 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Ecuador-Assorted Materials, 1980-1985; undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Ecuador-Cotopaxi Bilingual Schools, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Ecuador-Quichua Alphabetization, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Ecuador-Summer Institute of Linguistics, 1953-1980 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Finland, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Guatemala-Assorted Journal Articles, 1943-1982 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Guatemala-Assorted Materials, 1979-1985; undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Guatemala-Bilingual Education Teaching Materials, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Guatemala-Bilingual Education Project Materials, 1976; 1981-1988 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Guatemala-Demographic Studies, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Guatemala-Proyecto Lingüistico Francisco Marroquin, 1973-1985 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Guatemala-Reports on Bilingual Education, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Guatemala-Reports on Bilingual Education, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Guatemala-Reports on Bilingual Education, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Guatemala-Reports on Bilingual Education, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Guatemala-Reports on Bilingual Education, April 1983 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Guatemala-Reports on Bilingual Education, July 1983 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Guatemala-Reports on Bilingual Education, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Latin America, 1980; 1985 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Mexico-Assorted Journal Articles, 1977-1981 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - 8 Mexico-Assorted Materials, 1970-1985 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Mexico-Ethno linguistic Training Program, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Mexico-The Mexican Radioprimaria Project, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Mexico-Tarahumaras, 1971; undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Mexico-Bilingual Education Materials for Teachers, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Mexico-Bilingual Education Materials for Teachers, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Netherlands, 1970-1982 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - New Zealand, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Nigeria, 1976; 1979 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Panamá, undated (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Paraguay, 1976-1988 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Paraguay-Papers and Analyses, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Peru-Assorted Journal Articles, 1980; undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Peru-Assorted Materials, 1973-1980; undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Peru-Language Planning and Bilingual Education Booklets and Pamphlets, 1971-1981; undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Peru-Language Planning and Bilingual Education Materials, 1979-1986; undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Peru-Quechua Language Programs, 1980; 1986 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Peru-Reports, 1971-1979 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Peru-Rural Development, 1971-1983 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Philippines, 1984-1986 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Soviet Union, 1984; undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Sweden, 1973; 1975,; 1979 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Venezuela, undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - United Kingdom, 1961; 1966 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 6: Proposals
    - Assorted Proposals, 1980-1983; 1978,; undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - InterAmerica Research Associates-A Joint Venture Proposal in Response to an Information Clearinghouse for Bilingual Education, undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - InterAmerica Research Associates-Technical Proposal: Application of Automatic Data Processing in Bilingual Vocational Training Programs, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - InterAmerica Research Associates-Technical Proposal: Bilingual Effects of Community and Schools, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - InterAmerica Research Associates-Technical Proposal: A Descriptive Study of Significant Bilingual Instructional Features, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - InterAmerica Research Associates-Technical Proposal: Projection for Changes in Number of Persons with Limited English Language Proficiency, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Request for Proposal for the First Evaluation of the Bilingual Education Program, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - U.S Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1975-1979 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Subseries 7: United States
    - Alaska, 1979-1981 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Arizona-Assorted Materials, 1975-1983 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Arizona-Arizona State University-Materials for a Bilingual Education Program, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - California-Asian Bilingual Education, 1980-1981 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - California-Case Studies and Reports, 1976; 1984,; 1987 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - California-Legislation, 1976-1980 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - California-Materials for the State’s Master Plan for Bilingual Bicultural Education, 1973-1984 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - California-San Francisco-Assorted Materials, 1973-1975 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - California-San Francisco-Desegregation/Integration Materials, 1971-1973 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - California-San Francisco-Maps, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - California-San Francisco-Research by John B. Lum, 1978; undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Colorado, 1975-1984 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Connecticut, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Florida, 1978-1985 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Hawaii, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Illinois-Assorted Materials, 1976-1984 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Illinois-Case Studies and Reports, 1974-1980 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Illinois-Case Studies and Reports, 1981-1984 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Illinois-Handbooks and Summaries, 1976-1981 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Illinois-Chicago-Assorted Materials, 1975-1986 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Iowa, 1979-1980; undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Louisiana, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Maine, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Massachusetts, 1970-1980 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Michigan, 1979-1986 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Minnesota, 1974-1984 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Missouri, 1980; 1983 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - New Jersey, 1978-1982 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - New Mexico, 1970; 1976-1978,; undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - New York-Assorted Materials, 1974; 1976-1980 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - New York-Court Case Aspira V Board of Education of the City of New York Materials, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Oklahoma, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Rhode Island, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Texas-Assorted Materials, 1972-1983 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Texas-Bilingual Education Programs Prepared by U.S Office of Education, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Texas-Case Studies and Reports, 1975-1984 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Texas-Court Cases, 1978; 1981 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Texas- Materials for the State’s Master Plan for Bilingual Education, 1978-1983 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Texas-Austin-Assorted Materials, 1980; 1982,; undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Texas-Brownsville-Assorted Materials, 1975-1976 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Texas-Weslaco-Materials for Pilot Program for a Project on Bilingual Education, 1969-1970 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Virginia, 1978-1980 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Washington, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Washington D.C, undated (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Wisconsin, 1981; undated (Box 16, Folder 19)